原视频名：IFSCL - Théorie [Story Mode] 'Simone'
原作者名：Code LucPlayer
视频来源：youtu.be/vimcbKw2KGo
原视频发布日期：20180521
字幕根据原视频英文字幕制作
字幕翻译：Albeta，jky
Hello everyone, here is IcePlayer
大家好，我是IcePlayer
We are here for a new video format
我们来看一个新的视频格式
completely dedicated to the story mode of the IFSCL
专门用于讨论IFSCL的故事模式
This format isn't a recurring one
这种格式不会重现
Like the "Return to the past" or the "Code XANA"
就像"时间倒转"或者"Code XANA"那样
but will be more and more present on the channel
但会越来越频繁地出现在频道上
while information about the story mode will be revealed to us
但故事模式的秘密会揭示给我们吗
because the more info we have
因为我们掌握的信息越多
the more coherent and logic theories we can make
我们就能得出更有条理和逻辑性的理论
based on real elements given by Immu
基于Immu(IFSCL制作者)给出的真实素材
and not only ideas that we thought about
不单单是我们自己的想法
Those videos will always be presented approximately the same way
这些视频总是以近似相同的方式呈现
In the first part I will talk about all the elements that can be surely trusted
在第一部分中，我将讨论所有完全真实的要素
for the selected theory, as they are from official sources, which are the original show,
因为他们所选择的推理理论，其素材来源于官方消息，也就是原剧
the website Code Lyoko.fr or everything Immu said in the game, a trailer
还有网站Code Lyoko.fr或者Immu在游戏中的预告片里说的
or a post on facebook or discord or the game forum.
或者是在facebook，discord，游戏论坛上发布的帖子
In the second part, I will present you the theories that seem the most coherent
在第二部分，我将向大家介绍最符合逻辑的理论
In this videos, I will also credit the people with who I theorised
在这段视频中，我还要感谢与我一起构思的人
since I personnaly prefer make my theories with another person
因为我喜欢跟别人说说我的想法
to have an external point of view
这样我就能获得外部的一些观点
so I have the most exact and realistic theory based on the elements we have in our possession
所以基于我们所拥有的要素，我能得出最精确、最真实的理论
This first theory video will have as subject the name "Simone"
现在是第一段视频，主题是"Simone"，这个名字
that appeared for the first time in the anniversary trailer that celebrated the eight years of IFSCL.
首次出现在IFSCL八周年纪念的预告片中
We will try to understand
我们会努力去弄明白
who this name is referring to
这个名字指的是什么
and why we see it during the boot screen of the laboratory computer
以及为什么我们会在实验室电脑的启动屏幕上看到它
The theory presented in this video was imagined with "Appryl",
这个视频中的理论是我和"Appryl"推测出来的
an IFSCL and Code Lyoko fan since a long time
她是IFSCL和Code Lyoko的忠实粉丝
Let's go
让我们开始吧
To begin here is what we know for sure
首先，我们可以确定的是
about the word "Simone"
"Simone"这个词
In the show, only one character will be presented as "Simone",
在剧中，只有一个角色会以"Simone"的名字出现
which is the counseling psychologist of the Kadic school
那就是凯迪中学的心理咨询师
He is seen in only two episodes of the first season:
在第一季中他只出现了两集:
The episode 11 : "Plagued"
第11集：鼠患
And the episode 25 : "Code: Earth"
和第25集：代码 地球
But according to Code Lyoko.fr, his name is actually Hans Klotz,
但根据Code Lyoko.fr，他的名字其实是汉斯·克鲁兹
he had a secondary role in the 11th episode
他是第11集的配角
and is in the background in episode 25
在25集中，他出现在课堂的背景中
In the IFSCL, the name appeared in
在IFSCL里，这个名字出现在
the anniversary trailer for the game's 8th birthday
IFSCL游戏八周年纪念的预告片
but was also added in the texts that appear in the top-left corner when starting the interface since the version 3.6.0
但同时，从IFSCL 3.6.0版本开始，在超级计算机启动界面左上角出现的文本中也加上了这个名字
and it is specifically this that Appryl and I used to complete our theories about this name
我和Appryl就是通过这种方式来完善我们关于这个名字的理论
Here are the theories we imagined
下面是我们推理得出的理论
As previously said the name "Simone"
如前所述"Simone"这个名字
appears during the initialization of the lab computer in the 8th anniversary trailer of the IFSCL
出现在IFSCL八周年纪念预告片中的实验室计算机初始化期间
We could guess that it was a session in the supercomputer
我们大概可以猜出这是一个在超级计算机里的会话
ijust like Hopper's and Jeremie's
就像之前也出现了Hopper和Jeremie一样
But...
但是…
We weren't 100% sure
我们也不是百分百确定
It could also be a code, like
Simone也可能是一个密码，比如
the "SCIPIO" code to activate a command or something else
"SCIPIO"密码用来激活命令或其他东西
Also, we didn't have anything to put on date on when the word was typed
而且，我们也不会在打字的时候上加上日期
But with the version 3.6.0, we could answers some of these questions
但是在3.6.0版本中， 我们可以回答其中一些问题
As you saw on the previous picture
正如你在前一张图片上看到的
A lot of information appears when you start the interface
启动界面时会出现大量信息
and it really isn't new
这并不是什么新鲜事
These texts, even is not readable
而且这些文本又不可读
still appearing in the show,when the computer is turned on.
但在原剧中超级计算机开机时依然出现
Because of that,Immu took this element back in the first versions of the game
正因如此，Immu将这一要素带回游戏的最初版本
But it's only since the version 3.0.0
但这是从3.0.0版本才开始的
that the showed text becomes readable
在3.0.0版本中，之前显示的文本才可读
This text now shows which sessions have been opened on the supercomputer.
现在这个文本表示在超级计算机里，哪些会话已经开启过了
However as you can see
然而，正如你所看到的
It didn't show anything abnormal compared to what we already knew about the show
相较我们看过的原剧，它没有显示出任何异常
which is the first session created for Hopper
第一个会话是Hopper创建的
opened the 13th of April 1974
会话开启时间是1974年4月13日
Which is the official year when the Carthage project began
刚好是迦太基计划正式开始的那年
And the second session is Jeremie's
第二个会话是Jeremie的
opened the 9th of October 2001,
开启的时间是2001年10月9日
the official year when the show began
是原剧正式开始上映的年份
However with the version 3.6.0, the text changed for the first time since the 3.0.0
但是在3.6.0版本中， 文本发生了自3.0.0以来第一次变化
and this changed is definitely not random
这种改变绝对不是随意的
As we can see,  a lot of things have changed
正如我们所看到的，很多事情都发生了变化
We'll note specifically for our theory the appearance of a session opened before Hopper's.
我们会特别注意我们的理论中，出现的会话早于Hopper
Since Hopper's actual name is Waldo Franz (it's actually Walso Shaeffer)
因为Hopper的真名是Waldo Franz(其实也就是Walso Shaeffer)
the second session is effectively his
实际上第二个会话才是Hopper的
As you can see, the first session was opened with the name Simone
现在，第一个会话是用Simone开启的
From that we can be 99% sure that Simone is the name
这样的话，我们可以从99%可以确定Simone是个人名
of a real person,
一个真实存在的人
male or female, and not just a code, like Scipio
是男是女无法得知，但不会像Scipio那样，只是个暗号
Another very important thing, look at the dates : They changed.
还有一件很重要的事，我们来看看他们修改的日期
We can be sure that
我们可以肯定
that the dates given here correspond to the last time the session was opened.
这里显示的日期与上次会话开启的日期完全一致
It's verified easily with Franz's session since the last time he used the lab's computer
这就能证明该日期就是Franz最后一次使用实验室的电脑的日期
was June 6th 1994
那就是1994年6月6日
For Jeremie too, we know that the show ends In 2004
对于Jeremie来说，我们也知道这部剧在2004年完结
maybe not the 9th of October precisely but still in 2004
也许不是正好10月9日，但确实是在2004年完结的
So the last time Simone's session was opened was June 5th 1994
那么上次Simone的会话开始的时间是1994年6月5日
so the day before Hopper all the returns to the past did To create XANA and Lyoko.
所以Hopper在前一天所做的一切都回到了过去 包括创造XANA和Lyoko
It means that after this date no one else logged in on this session
这意味着在这个日期之后 没有人进入过这个会话
neither Simone Franz or Jeremie
不是Simone，也不是Franz或者Jeremie
Every information given about Simone until now isn't recognized as true by Immu
到目前为止我们关于Simone的猜测，lmmu并不是非常认同
but with the elements we have
但是有了这些要素
We can consider they're sure to make theories a lot more uncertain
我们也可以让他们的理论更加站不稳脚
So Simone is a person
所以我们还是认为Simone是一个人物
who own a session on the supercomputer
他拥有超级计算机上的会话
We also know the session was last opened in June 5th 1994
我们还知道会话最后在1994年6月5日打开
So just one real day before Hopper's
就在Hopper进行时间倒转的前一天
but 2546 days for the supercomputer.
这2546天对于超级计算机来说
As you know Hopper made 2546 returns to the past
意思就是Hopper启动了第2546次时间倒转
June 6th 1994 before going to Lyoko with Aelita
1994年6月6日他和Aelita去Lyoko之前
and leave the time continue normally
才让时间正常进行
Then, a few things have to be defined
然后，还有一些事情需要明确
Was Simone an ally or an enemy
Simone是盟友还是敌人
Is he dead, did he escaped
他死了吗，或者他逃走了吗
Or was he a victim of the Hopper first return to the past Hopper did
或者他因为Hopper启动的时间倒转程序
June 6th 1994 and forgot about the supercomputer
在1994年6月6日忘记了关于超级计算机的所有事情
and never came back to the factory
也没有再回到工厂
and finally what was their role and relation with
最后是他们的角色之间的关系
With these different hypotheses
有了这些不同的假设
Here is what seemed to Appryl and myself the most likely
我提一下我和Appryl的想法 也是最可能的情况
If Simone was Hopper's ally, then
如果Simone是Hopper的盟友，那么
they probably helped for creating the supercomputer
他们可能共同创造了超级计算机
In fact, even if Hopper is a real genuis, it seems
这样想确实有道理，因为即使Hopper是一个真正的天才
it seems difficult to imagine that he built the machine alone
但依然很难想象这台机器是他一个人造的
At least at the hardware level
至少在硬件方面上是这样的
As Jeremie said, you don't find a nuclear battery in the first shop
正如Jeremie所说，你不会随便进一家商店就能找到核电池这种东西
And Hopper had to find one
不过Hopper必须找到一枚核电池
to create his supercomputer, the one we see in episode 37 "Common Interest"
来创造他的超级计算机，就是我们在第37集共同利益 那里看到的那块
and of course all the high-technology material that had to be found and bought to build the supercomputer
而且，为了建造超级计算机所需要的高科技材料都得想办法找到并安装上去
As you know, a machine like this one doesn't run on an Intel Core i7
很显然，像这样的机器肯定不会运行在英特尔酷睿i7上
Also, the fact that Simone helped Hopper at least up to the 6th of June can be logic
Simone帮助Hopper这个事实至少到6月6日都是符合逻辑的
since the supercomputer, the scanners,
因为超级计算机，扫描仪
the holomap etc... was created before the 6th of June
全息地图等等……这些是在6月6日之前创建的
It's after the 6th of June that Hopper creates Lyoko, XANA, transfer programs etc...
6月6日之后，Hopper创造了Lyoko, XANA， 传送程序等等……
As only the software part of the supercomputer isn't affected by the returns to the past,
因为时间倒转不会使超级计算机的软件部分受到影响
which is confirmed many times in episodes
这个特性在原剧里被证实了很多次
Because otherwise we would have a supercomputer
否则我们的这台超级计算机
that would disassemble itself at each return to the past
每次时间倒转都会自我解体
which would have been a problem
这样的话就有问题了
To create Lyoko, XANA and everything at the software level in the supercomputer
创造Lyoko，XANA和一切都和超级计算机的软件水平有关
it seems logic that Hopper did it alone
这样看来，Hopper一个人完成是很有可能的
But to collect the hardware, the help of someone was probably necessary
但是要收集硬件的话，那就可能需要有人提供帮助
which is where we got the idea of this character
所以我们就是这样想到这个角色的
His disappearance is still hard to explain
他的消失至今仍难以解释
The most likely is that this person is dead
最有可能的是这个人已经死了
which would kind of explain
这样大概可以解释的通了
the fact that the warriors know the Return to the past can't bring back to life
Lyoko战士都知道，时间倒转不能让人死而复生
the dead. Hopper would have said it in his diary or
对于死者，Hopper会在日记里记载，或者
would have written it somewhere (most liekly since LW know this season 1)
可能写在什么地方了(很可能因为LW已经知道了（第一季中）)
because he had the experience
因为他有这个经验（火车站暂存）
The escape is also a possibility
逃跑也是一种可能性
Hopper may have asked the person to escape
Hopper可能叫那个人逃走了
because he knew the risks he was getting them into
因为他知道自己给他们带来了极大的风险
and after discovering the return to the past
在发现时间倒转之后
he knew he would have all the time necessary
他知道他有足够的时间
to create Lyoko and Xana. Also, the hardware part of the supercomputer was already done
创造Lyoko和Xana，而且超级计算机硬件部分已经完成了
and we think it is the part that was the most complicated
我们认为这个环节是最复杂的
he didn't need Simone's help anymore, which explains their disappearance
他不再需要Simone的帮助了，这样就解释了他失踪的原因
Finally, it seems hard to explain
最后，这似乎很难解释
that Simone didn't come back because of the first return to the past made by Hopper
Simone没回来是因为 Hopper的第一次时间倒转
because he would have only forgotten the last 24 hours and
因为他只会忘记 过去24小时之内发生的事情
if he really helped Hopper to create the supercomputer,
如果他真的帮助Hopper创造了超级计算机
he had probably been doing it for months even years
他可能已经做了好几个月甚至好几年
The big issue with this theory is that it doen't have anything to do with the original show
这个理论存在的最大问题是，它没有和原剧有关的任何内容
Hopper never said he received help in the parts of the diary we say in the anime
我们在动画里没看到Hopper在日记里有提到过他得到了谁的帮助
But we know Immu is gonna create new ones so
但我们知道Immu会制造新的情节
It could easily be integrated in the show story
并让它可以很容易地融入原剧的故事中
We also know Immu wants to put more dark in the story than in the original show
我们也知道Immu想在游戏情节中加入比原剧更多黑暗元素
so Simone's death to explain their disappearance
所以用Simone的死来解释他们的失踪
seems really possible even if in the few diary videos
即便是在那仅有的几段日记视频里，看起来可能性非常大
from Hopper diary we can see in the show, he doesn't look like he lost someone recently.
从Hopper的视频日记里我们可以看到，他看起来并不像是最近失去了谁
So Here is what we can say about Simone if we consider this character is one of Franz's ally
所以，这就是我们认为这个角色是Franz的盟友的理由
Now here is an interpretation in the opposite case
不过，这里又有一个与之相反的情况
If Simone was an enemy it would probably mean
如果Simone是敌人那就意味着
that the character was part of the men in black's organization
这个角色是黑衣人组织的一份子
who we see several times in the show,
我们在原剧中见过几次，
this organization was looking for Hopper
这个组织在找Hopper
to stop him from slowing down the Carthage project
并阻止他妨碍迦太基计划
this theory would have as a base a part of Franz's diary in the show
这个理论将原剧中Franz日记的一部分作为的基础
Here is what he says
他是这么说的
June 6th 1994, Day 1265
1994年6月6日, 第1265天
Someone is watching me, someone who wants to eliminate me
有人在监视我，有人想除掉我
As you can see, this person could be Simone, who would have found the factory
如你所见，这个人可能就是Simone，因为他会找到工厂
and would have logged on the supercomputer
并登陆超级计算机
but still several questions remain
不过这个理论仍然存在几个问题
Like why does Hopper
比如Hopper为什么
only realises he is being spied on only after 1265 returns to the past.
在1265次时间倒转之后才发现自己被人监视
Let me remind you that normally even if the men in black chased Hopper,
我来提醒你们一下，即使黑衣人追捕Hopper
it should have been impossible to catch him
按照常理是不可能抓到他的
since after each return to the past, they would forget everything they would have found about him
因为每次时间倒转之后，都会忘记他们发现关于Hopper的一切事情
and the would begin their day without noticing
他们会不知不觉地开始新的一天
So technically if Hopper wasn't spied on the first June 6th 1994 when he launched the first return to the past,
所以严格来说，Hopper如果没有在1994年6月6日第一次时间倒转前被监视
he shouldn't be neither
他就永远不会发现自己被监视
June 6th 1994 after 1265 returns to the past
如果说1994年6月6日1265次时间倒转后Hopper才发现自己被监视的话
but it seems it's not the case, this necessarily mean
那么事情就是另一回事了，因为这意味着
that the men in black found a way to cancel the returns to the past effects, which seems logic
黑衣人找到了办法解除时间倒转所带来是失忆效果，这样看起来是合乎逻辑的
since during 2545 days,
这样一来，在2545次时间倒转中
no one came looking for Hopper at his house but
没人去Hopper家找他，但是
the 2546th day, the men in black found the Hermitage
在第2546天，黑衣人发现了隐居之所
This problem having a solution, there are two more to solve
这个问题已经解决了，还有两个问题需要解决
First, if this spy is Simone, how can we explain
首先，如果这个间谍是Simone，我们该怎么解释
that he opened his session the 5th of July even if Hopper made the returns to the past the 6th
他在6月5日打开会话，即使Hopper在6号启动了时间倒转
The only solution would be that the return launched by Hopper didn't come back the 6th of June
唯一能解释的通的，是Hopper发起的时间倒转时间没有回到6月6日
but the 5th, late the evening
而是回到了5号晚上
Hopper would go back to his house
这样的话Hopper会回自己的家
and would only come back the 6th to work. He recorded the diary the 6th of June,
然后在6号回去工作，并将6号发生的事情写进了日记
as the show wants,Simone would have used the computer the 5th of June the evening
然后，如剧组所愿，Simone在6月5日使用了电脑
Now the second problem is from the spying itself,
现在第二个问题来自于间谍活动本身
If Simone, one of the men in black's agent,
如果Simone是黑衣人的探员之一
who hopper was talking about,
Hopper说的想除掉他的那个人
why did they take 1281 days exactly to come get him at the Hermitage
他们为什么正好在第1281次时间倒转的时候到隐居之所去找他
Why didn't they come earlier, if they already knew at the 1265th day that Hopper was working on the supercomputer
如果他们早就已经知道，Hopper在第1265次时间倒转时开始研制超级计算机，为什么不早点来
We can answer this questions with two hypotheses
我们可以用两个假设来回答这个问题
Either Hopper literally got rid of Simone
要么Hopper真的把Simone干掉了
Either he blanked their memory
要么是他消除了他们的记忆
and their way of not being affected by the return to the past
以及他们不被时间倒转所影响的方式
Of course, Hopper did it very quickly
当然，Hopper行动非常迅速
because the spy didn't have the time to tell the others men in black
这样的话，Simone就没时间去告诉其他黑衣人
when you see the time they took or maybe this spy didn't work for the men in black,
如果你认为他们在这段时间里碌碌无为或者Simone不是为黑衣人效劳的
it's also possible.
这么说也说得过去
As you can see the theory that says Simon is an ally seems closer to the reality
如此 说Simone是盟友的理论 似乎更切实一些
but it has the disadvantage of
但这个理论也有漏洞
having no possible insertion in the official show
它不能插入到原剧中
where a spy is already here in the show.
因为剧中已经有一个间谍了
Now you have the two main theories we can put on this person right now
现在有两个可以成立的理论
Of course, some of you might make the link to the story of the the Code Lyoko Chronicles
当然，你们当中有些人可能会在虚幻勇士编年史 中找到这个故事的关联
where it is said that Suzanne Hertz, from her real name Steinback,
那个小说里说Suzanne Hertz，真名为Steinback
helps Franz Hopper to create the supercomputer.
她帮助Franz Hopper 创造了超级计算机
It is true that her first name isn't mentionned
这里没有提到她的名字
so it could easily be Simone but Immu clearly stated on Discord that
所以帮忙的人也有可能是Simone，但Immu明确表示
he didn't consider the Code Lyoko Chronicles as part of the story
他的游戏情节没有参考虚幻勇士编年史 的内容
so there is no chance Simone is actually Ms Hertz
所以Simone不可能是Hertz
However, he said he read the first book
然而，他说他读了虚幻勇士编年史 的第一本书
which could explain similarities with the Chronicles story
这可以解释该情节与该小说的相似性
Another annex fact, even if the two theories stated previously are wrong
从另一个角度来说, 即使之前的两个理论都是错误的
the fact that Simone is a real person
Simone也还是一个真实存在的人
who has a session on the supercomputer proves at least one thing
且拥有超级计算机上的会话，这就足以证明他是真实存在的人
My idea that the different things we see in the 8th anniversary trailer
我的想法是 我们在IFSCL八周年的预告片中所看到的内容
come from different periods of the show
来源于原剧的各个片段
is a little more confirmed
这样似乎更有说服力
We would have the lab computer with the name Simone which would be the past of the show
我们在预告片中看到实验室电脑的名字是Simone
just like Hopper's suitcase
就像Hopper的行李箱一样
The Jeremie we see in the trailer
我们在预告片中看到的Jeremie
has the same age as the one on the show, and finally
和原剧里的Jeremie年龄一样大，最后呢
the smartphone we see would come from the future compared to the show timeline
我们看到的智能手机将来自于相对于原剧时间线的未来
but that's a little off-subject
但这有点偏离主题了
We now have said everything there is to say about the name
关于这个名字，我们已经说完了所有想说的话
Simone with all the elements we had in our possession.
我们已经掌握了Simone和所有的要素
I invite you to talk about your own theories in comments about this name
我邀请你在评论中，发表关于这个名字的你自己的想法
to see if you agree with Appryl and me or if you think we're wrong.
看看你是否同意我和Appryl 或者你认为我们错了
Thereupon, I'm saying see you very soon
那么，我就只能说再见了
For next videos, and of course
当然，我是说下个视频见
Ciao the Lyoko Warriors
Lyoko战士们，再见